Last time, we defined a model, and next,
上次我们定义了一个模型
I want to actually instantiate it and train it using our training data.
下面我将实例化该模型并使用训练数据训练它
First, I'll specify my model hyperparameters.
首先指定模型超参数
The input and output will just be one,
输入和输出大小为 1
it's just one sequence at a time that we're processing and outputting,
一次处理和生成一个序列
then I'll specify a hidden dimension which is just the number
然后指定隐藏维度
of features expect to generate with the RNN layer.
也就是希望 RNN 层级生成的特征数量
I'll set this to 32, but for a small data set like this,
设为 32 但是对于这样的小型数据集来说
I may even be able to go smaller.
甚至可以设为更小的值
I'll set n_layers to one for now.
暂时将 n_layers 设为 1
So, I'm not stacking any RNN layers.
不叠加任何 RNN 层级
I'll create this RNN and printed out.
创建并输出此 RNN
I should see the variables that I expect.
结果应该是我期望的值
My RNN layer with an input size and hidden dimension,
这是 RNN 层级的输入大小和隐藏维度
and a linear layer with an input number of features and output number.
这是线性层级的输入特征数量和输出数量
Before training, I'm defining my loss and optimization functions.
在开始训练之前 定义损失和优化函数
Now in this case, we're training our model to generate
我们将训练模型生成数据点
data points that are going to be basically coordinate values.
这些数据点是坐标值
So to compare a predicted and ground truth point like this,
为了比较预测数据点和真实数据点
we'll use a regression loss because this is
我们将使用回归损失
just a quantity rather than something like a class probability.
因为它只是一个数量
So for the loss function,
而不是类别概率
I'm going to use mean squared error loss which will
我将使用均方误差损失
just measure the distance between two points.
它会衡量两个点之间的距离
I'll use an Adam optimizer which is standard for recurrent models,
我将使用 Adam 优化器 它是递归模型的标准优化器
passing in my parameters and our learning rate.
传入参数和学习速率
Next, I have a function train that's going to take
下面是 train 函数
in and RNN a number of steps to train for,
它将接受一个 rnn 和训练步数
and the parameter that will determine when it will print out law statistics.
以及何时输出损失信息的参数
Now, at the very start of this function,
在此函数开头
I'm initializing my hidden state.
初始化隐藏状态
At first, this is going to be nothing and it will default to a hidden state of all zeros.
一开始设为 None隐藏状态默认全为 0
Then let's take a look at our batch loop.
然后是批次循环
Now, this is a little unconventional,
这个循环不太符合常规
but I'm just generating data on the fly
根据训练步数
here according to how many steps we will train for.
动态生成数据
So, in these lines, I'm just generating a sequence of 20 sine wave values at a time.
在这几行一次生成 20 个正弦波值序列
As we saw when I generated data at the start.
和在开头生成数据一样
Here, I'm getting my input x and a target
在这里获取输入 x 以及目标 y
y that's just shifted by one time step in the future.
y 只是比 x 晚一个时间步
Here, I'm converting this data into tensors and
在这里将数据转换为张量
squeezing the first dimension of our x_tensor to give it a batch size of one.
压缩张量 x 的第一个维度 使其批次大小为 1
Then I can pass my input tensor into my RNN model.
然后将输入张量传入 rnn 模型
So this is taking in my x input tensor and my initial hidden state at first.
rnn 接受的是输入张量 x 和初始隐藏状态
It produces a predicted output and a new hidden state.
生成预测参数和新的隐藏状态
Next is an important part.
下面是很重要的部分
I want to feed this new hidden state into the RNN as
当我们在下个时间步再次循环时
input at the next time step when we loop around once more.
我希望将此新隐藏状态当做输入传入 rnn 中
So I'm just copying the values from this produced hidden state into a new variable.
将生成的隐藏状态中的值复制到新的变量中
This essentially detaches the hidden state from its history and I will
这样可以将隐藏状态与其历史记录分离开
not have to backpropagate through a series of accumulated hidden states.
不用反向传播一系列累积的隐藏状态
So this is what's going to be passed as input to
所以在下个时间步（序列的下个数据点）
the RNN at the next time step or next point in our sequence.
将它传入 rnn 中
So then, I have the usual training commands,
然后是正常的训练命令
I zero out any accumulated gradients.
清零累积的梯度
Calculate the loss, and perform a backpropagation in optimization step.
计算损失 执行反向传播和优化步骤
Down here, I have some code to print out the loss
在下面输出损失
and show what our input and predicted outputs are.
并显示输入和预测输出
Finally, this function returns a trained RNN
最后 此函数返回训练过的 rnn
which will be useful if you want to save a model for example.
你可以保存该模型
So, let's run this code.
我们来运行下代码
I'll choose to train our RNN,
训练在上面定义的 rnn
and that we defined above for 75 steps.
并训练 75 步
I'll print out the result every 15 steps.
每隔 15 步输出结果
We can see the mean squared error loss here and the
这里输出了均方误差损失
difference between our red input in our blue output values.
并显示了红色输入值和蓝色输出值之间的区别
Recall that we want the blue output values to be
我们希望蓝色输出值
one times step in the future when compared to the red ones.
比红色输入值晚一个时间步
So it starts out pretty incorrect.
所以一开始完全错了
Then we can see the loss decreases quite a lot after the first 15 steps.
在 15 个时间步之后 损失降低了很多
Our blue line is getting closer to our red one.
蓝色虚线更接近红色虚线
As we train the blue predicted line gets closer to what we know our target is,
继续训练之后 蓝色预测虚线与已知目标更接近
at the end of 75 steps,
在 75 步之后
our loss is pretty low.
损失很低了
Our blue line looks very similar to what we know or output should be.
蓝色虚线和已知目标/真实输出很相似
If we look at the same time step for a red input dot,
查看同一时间步的红色输入点
and a blue input dot,
和蓝色输入点
we we shouldn't see that the blue input is
应该看到蓝色输入
one time-step shifted in the future. It's pretty close.
比红色输入晚了一个时间步很接近了
You could imagine getting even better performance after training for
如果训练更多个时间步或添加更多层级
more steps or if you wanted to add more layers to your RNN.
RNN 的效果应该会更好
So, in this video,
在此视频中
I wanted to demonstrate the basic structure of a simple RNN and show you how
我希望能演示简单 RNN 的基本结构
to keep track of the hidden state and represent memory over time as you train.
并演示如何在训练过程中记录隐藏状态及表示记忆功能
You could imagine doing something very similar with data about
你可以对其他数据执行非常相似的操作
world temperature or stock prices which are a little bit more complicated than this.
例如全球气温或股价 这些数据更复杂
But it will be really interesting to see if you could
如果能通过查看给定的这些数据
predict the future given that kind of data.
然后预测未来情形 那就很有意思了
Okay, so this is just an example,
这只是一个例子
you can check out this code in our program GitHub,
你可以在我们的程序 GitHub 中查看此代码
which is linked to below.
下方提供了链接
I encourage you to play around with
建议你尝试不同的模型参数
these model parameters until you have a good handle on
直到你充分了解
the dimensions of an RNN input and
RNN 输入和输出的维度
output and how hyperparameters might change, how this model trains.
明白超参数会如何变化以及如何训练模型
Next, Matt and I will go over an exercise in generating text.
接下来 我和 Matt 将介绍如何生成文本